# **Drew Johnston**

Web Application Architect and Engineer

## Motivation

I love to create solutions that simplify complex and interesting business problems to make everyone's life easier. Most of my 15 years of experience is in creating custom backend solutions. I'm interested in places that can take full advantage of my development team management, as well as my extensive application development experience and skillset, to allow me to continue to grow.



## Qualifications

- Self-motivated, knowledgeable, experienced developer with a strong e-commerce background and management experience.
- Many times experienced in building web applications from the ground-up, using best practices, the latest technologies and with scalability in mind.
- Self-taught, fast learner, solution-oriented.
- Excellent communicator with demonstrated organizational, leadership and mentoring abilities.

## **Contact Information**

Katy, TX 281-799-1722 drew@johnston.us drewjoh.com github.com/drewjoh linkedin.com/drewjoh

## Skills

PHP / MySQL Javascript Git Management HTML / CSS Scaling DevOps Caching APIs Nginx Redis Memcached Bootstrap Networking A/B Testing IT Consulting

## Education

Studied Computer Engineering Harding University 2001-2003

PayPal Certified Developer

## Experience

2012 TO PRESENT Software Architect & Senior Lead Developer Photojojo / Zoomin

- o Fulfilled all development needs as the sole developer for 2.5 years.
- Solely responsible for interviewing, hiring, on-boarding, mentoring and supporting two developers.
- Planned, assigned and executed a complete rewrite of an 8-year-old legacy e-commerce system that would allow us to be flexible and grow into new business opportunities.
- o Given full authority and responsibility for architecting and building the new system which included:
  - a front and backend for physical & electronic products with order management
  - multiple warehouse support
  - inventory management and tracking of all individual pieces
  - data analytics across all aspects of the business
  - scalable infrastructure, utilizing independent and grouped servers for different functions (admin, API, frontend, cron/worker)
  - multiple brand/website support utilizing a single backend/database
- Went from first Git commit to launch in 5 months; imported all legacy data.
- Saved incredibly costly and rigid vendor lock-in with 3rd party hosted backend services.
- Managed the Houston, TX office that supported three developers.
- Managed all DevOps related admin. (Servers, Email, DNS, CDN, Automated Deployments, etc.)
- Given entire responsibility and decision making authority for all things related to development, technology choices and priorities surrounding business aspects that involved these things. Everything ranging from what payment processor to use (and negotiating our rates), to what our security policies/practices are, to what hosting provider to go with, to what customer support SaaS we use.

### 2001 TO PRESENT Owner / App Developer / IT Consultant Happy Cloud, LLC

- Created a custom e-commerce solution. Optimized shipping processes to bring the package & ship time per order from ~3 minutes to ~20 seconds. (2005 - 2006)
- Created a custom doctor/patient scheduling and video conference SaaS. Included a custom, secure (HIPPA compliant), embedded video conference software. Scalable to many doctor and clinics across the US. Helped the company land investors and launch. (2008)
- Created and continue to maintain a custom daycare management & invoicing web application for a high end day care chain in Houston, TX. (2011 - Present)
- o Continue to support all hardware & networking for a daycare chain in Houston, TX. (2006 Present)
- Various client website designs, integrations and projects.
- Server setup and administration for all projects.

#### 2008 - 2012 Owner / Partner Coobo Media

- o Responsible for all website coding and application development.
- Responsible for all server administration.
- o Did business administration and finance.
- Created many custom web applications, from CMS's to online subscription services for digital products.
- o Implemented a custom VoIP PBX solution for the office utilizing Asterisk; saved hundreds per month using a SIP Trunk instead of paying a phone company.

#### References

#### **SUNNY RAO CEO Zoomin**

o <u>sunny@zoomin.com</u>

## AMIT GUPTA Original Owner Photojojo

o me@amitgupta.com

## JEN GIESE President / CEO Photojojo

jkgiese@gmail.com

KEVIN SISCO Software Developer / Business Partner / Personal Reference Shell Oil

kevin.sisco@gmail.com

**EMILY COSNOTTI** General Manager **Parabo Press** (sister company to Photojojo)

emilycosnotti@gmail.com

#### **AUSTIN ANDREWS** Developer **Photojojo**

o <u>A5mercuryhu@gmail.com</u>

## PHILIP JOHNSTON Developer Photojojo

o philjoh11@gmail.com